

Senior Software Engineer

☑ milad72t@gmail.com

? Tehran, Iran

Profiles: in **a** ? •

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with over six years of experience in e-commerce and billing companies. Experienced in migrating from monolithic to microservices and familiar with the microservices pattern. My expertise lies in PHP, SQL, and NoSQL, and I am enthusiastic about learning and utilizing my skills to develop innovative and efficient solutions.

EXPERIENCES

Digikala ~3 yrs

Senior Software Engineer - Platform team

October 2020 - Present

- o Digikala Group is the largest e-commerce platform in the Middle East with +40M visitors and +5M orders per month.
- As a member of the platform(core) team, engaged in providing the infrastructure for migrating to microservices that support 20k RPS by bringing new technologies and developing our customized framework.
- Innovated a CQRS service for products that handle more than 5K RPS.
- Configured and integrated the Apache APISIX gateway that handles 30k requests as the entry point to more than 50 services.
- Rewrote shopping APIs and refactor legacy codes of digikala.com resulting in a 40% reduction in resource requests.
- o Designed & Developed social e-commerce called Magnet which is like Instagram, and currently has over 1 million users and ~100k posts created per month.
- o Participated in onboarding new joiners, hiring process, and revising team structure.
- o Main used technologies: PHP, MySQL, Kafka, Redis, Kubernetes, Gitlab CI/CD, Elasticsearch, MongoDB, Debezium

Andishe Computer

3 yrs

Backend Software Engineer

September 2017 - October 2020

- Launched a billing system that is used by electricity Companies that handles the data of over 10M Power subscribers from all over the country
- Created subscriber surveillance and bill payment system that has all energy subscriber's data intended to remove bill papers (bargheman.com)
- o Structured an automated payment processing system, that gathers financial data from different banks (~2k documents per day) to transmit them to each power distribution and generate financial reports, which removed the need for human work.
- Main used technologies: Laravel, SQLServer, Docker, MongoDB, Redis, Python, C++

Behpardaz Pishro 6 mth

Backend Software Engineer

April 2017 - September 2017

- Completed a system ordered by the Ministry of Power for gathering information about 32M subscribers of electricity from all over the country, generating reports on the data.
- o Main used technologies: Laravel, Oracle, MongoDB

SKILLS

- o Proficient in PHP
- o Proficient in relational databases (SQL) and Database Design
- Experienced with Microservices patterns (API-GW, SAGA, CQRS, Event Sourcing)
- o Experienced with NoSQL databases (Redis, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Memcached, InfluxDB)
- Experienced with Docker, Kubernetes, Gitlab CI/CD, Debezium, Kafka and Git
- Experienced with Python, Golang, and C++
- o Experienced with Linux and Server maintenance

EDUCATION

Iran University of Science and Technology

Master of Computer Networks engineering - Second Rank, 17.89 GPA

2016-2018

Iran University of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Computer engineering - Third Rank, 16.85 GPA

2012-2016